welcome to the stoa
the stoa is a digital campfire where we
cohere
and dialogue about what matters most at
the knife's edge
of what's happening now
oh let's do some check-ins um
when i saw a cure i started getting this
badass energy and i just went like fuck
yeah
the dawn has arrived um welcome
to the stoa i'm peter limberg the
steward of the stoa
and this is a place for us to cohere and
dialogue about what matters most at the
knife's edge
of this moment and today we have a very
very special guest
my new friend akira the dawn and how
this is gonna work
um me and akira uh maybe just jam chat
i'm really curious to understand his
world and reality because he's a very
fucking interesting person
and then uh we're gonna jump on to his
uh live link i don't know how we're
gonna do that i think he's just gonna
send us in the chat box and we'll just
head over there
at that half hour click the link baby
yeah hyperlinks okay um
so one thing when you and i were
chatting after uh the alley session
um was we're talking about darkness and
lightness
and how it's so important to understand
the dark
in order to um feel the light in a way
and in your whole kind of like some
people might be surprised about that
with you because you know you're just
like meaning wave so optimistic it's so
fun it's so light
um so i'm curious if you could speak a
little bit more on that
yeah well uh the reason yeah we were
talking about this right and the reason
i am so optimistic and the reason i can
walk around
saying uh this is the big recorded human
civilization and it's a beautiful days
of your life every damn day
and mean it is because i looked the
darkness
square face and saw as much of it as was
there for me to see
that i could with the existence i had
which was a lot
and uh as jocko willink
put it in something i sampled on the
album i did with him now that i've seen
how dark it can get i truly appreciate
the light in the world
and you can actually appreciate the
light in the world until you've looked
at the darkness for all that it is
and i think that's something we're all
kind of doing collectively at the moment
on a level that we haven't
done for a few generations at least
yeah i totally agree with that and i'm
curious how you navigate with
discernment
about how much you reveal about the
darkness
i think it's a bit like djing in general
you need to read the room
i kind of think of lots of things in
terms of djing probably because that's
what one of the things that i've done
but i've seen it applies to many things
and uh you want to read the room and
sometimes it's appropriate and sometimes
it's not appropriate and sometimes it's
useful and helpful and sometimes it's
really not
being useful and helpful
yeah yeah i agree with that too um so
how do you
last seven years certain conversations
weren't
the right ones to be having and now they
are again yeah
yeah does that make sense yeah it does
um so i think you're talking to
this about your musical sensibilities
your artistic sensibilities that gives
you the capacity to read the room
to have that discernment to see who can
receive the message
of darkness um so how do you think
how do you gain that discernment
yourself personally and how maybe other
people can gain it
in the context of djing right it's um
you've got a group of people and you
want them all to have
uh the optimal time and if you're really
going in and you want to have a
transcendent experience
you know and there's lots of different
people in the room and they like
different things
and they're at different points in their
life and there are different point in
their development
and there are different points in their
journeys but they're all here in this
place and there's the potential for
something amazing to occur
and if you do the right things in the
right sequence uh
you can create something wonderful and
beautiful and useful
and then walk off into their lives at
the end of that night and they go into
the next week and they go with a
with a useful brilliant energy that they
can carry with into their lives
and if you do it really well they can
carry that shit for their whole lives
and they'll have that on their deathbed
and it's okay so it's not a thing where
you could go in
and have a preconceived idea of what the
right records are going to be
you have to work it out from what's
going on at the time who's there what
the vibes is who's in the place
sometimes you have to counteract a
negative energy with a different energy
sometimes you have to counteract too
much masculine energy with some female
energy or whatever it is
that so doing that every night
for thousands of nights i don't know how
many nights but doing that you know you
learn to do that and then you start to
see how that applies to the rest of the
world and the rest of the life
and sometimes you want to talk about a
thing but it's not the right time to
talk about things sometimes you know
about some stuff
sometimes you really know some stuff and
you want to scream it from the god damn
rooftops but it's not going to be useful
at that moment to screen that stuff
the people are not going to be receptive
the message will not be well received
in the context of our content of what's
going on right now
you had to have a bunch of things happen
like for example jordan peterson to come
along and start a bunch of conversations
for things that are now occurring to be
able to occur right
if that makes sense you know i mean you
had to like lay that foundation play
those earlier records you can't just
step on the deck like step in and
play like the 2am like the one in the
morning dance floor smash
before everyone has gotten the fucking
vibes yeah
you got to clear the way a little bit um
so
with peterson you've been reading some
of my my recent journals and you know
he's
my former therapist um and i mentioned
them he's sort of like
my sense of him now is that he tapped
into some primordial language
and he could speak it and it sounds like
what you were talking you tapped into
that as a dj
does that resonate i think that's what
we're all doing
uh jeff smith he used to write a local
rigorous intuition
uh the last time it was william which
some of your writing reminded me of
um the last time it was this weird in
sort of 2005 to 2012 that period
um he talked about as being wet brained
receivers of non-localized consciousness
you know they're all like receiving
stuff that kind of already exists when
i'm writing a song it feels like i'm
just pulling something that's already
there out of the air
which is true if you think of in terms
of frequency and on and off and on and
off and all that sort of thing
the potential is already there uh you
know if you're carving
a great uh statute it already exists
you've just got to hit the
block at the right places to let the
thing that's already there reveal itself
um and so when in your development
did you start like being able to speak
this primordial language
and i guess how did that coincide with
understanding the darkness that you know
about
uh i wouldn't even say i don't even know
if i can still speak it you know i
i uh i just work continuously
and keep moving in the manner of a shark
uh
so i kind of got in the zone at one
point and i've just
been in there for a while so i don't
know if i was to fall out of this thing
if i'd be able to get back in
i don't know if i could really really
write it down in a way that would be
clear for someone else to understand i
try
and i'm trying that every day um but
as far as the the the darkness thing
uh when i first got internet i was one
of the people who fell down the darkness
holes
you know because and i went all in and
sort of went really down there and then
it was already
it aligned with things i knew from my
own life and things i'd seen in my life
i left home very early was homeless and
things of that nature so i saw some
size of the world and i maneuvered in
some communities and i hang out with
very very some very very
rich people and some very very poor
people and i saw all sorts of goings on
that then aligned with the things i was
discovering through these kind of
investigations in the early days of the
internet and as
you would saw you spoke uh something
about this in your blog has something
about like the last
9 11 was something like this feeling but
everyone wasn't online
in the same way then everyone wasn't all
connected together in the same way then
as you and i were talking about the way
some of us were in those
those days when the internet first
appeared that's now ev
that's normies that's your auntie that's
your uncle and when i say normies i
don't mean it disparagingly man
my wife was sensitive she's like you
keep talking about normies people
i think i like normies i want like
normally just means regular people
but regularly are now doing the sorts of
like terrifying investigations some of
us out there on the weird fringes we're
doing
uh between 2005 and 2012. they're all
doing it they're all locked up open
doors
they've got internet uh they're making
these dark voyages
the soul and finding all this stuff
you know those of us who've already been
there uh
you know our job should be to uh
to kind of help help
away from the abyss stuff and teasing
over
so uh i'm going to stop myself from my
desire to keep
the inquiry going i will ask you for the
questions but if anyone has questions
in the chat box to hear or just
statements that they want to make just
um write it down and then you know just
yourself i'm not um very good at zoom
yet
you don't have to do anything you don't
do anything you just have to look pretty
um
and which is not too hard my friend and
then people can just write
in the chat box and then i'll call them
to mute themselves um
so uh what is um
[Music]
your sense of how things are gonna
unfold with the normies
uh and then grocking the darkness
and what rocking the darkness did you do
uh understanding i said grocking
understanding
oh i don't have understanding is even
possible but uh accepting
i would say it's accepting you know for
a lot of people that would like
the idea that there really is that
shadow side of everything that real
real shadow side that's as bad as good
is good
uh lots of people would never even
really want to contemplate that and
never had to
you know a lot of people never had now
some people have some people have had
experiences in their life they just
fought
this really right but if we're going
through a situation now where
way more people a tipping point
percentage of people
are going to be faced with that and
forced to accept it it's the accept
acceptance bit that's important and then
the integration
of that as as just a part of existence
and then how you can turn that into
something
useful you know how you can create that
balance in the force that
george lucas so eloquently spoke about
when he uh
translated joseph campbell's work into
some movies
right and hijacked culture in the 70s
so this is what failed in their current
iterations of trying to
try to take those things and twist them
to their ends the current disney star
wars model for example
has tried to take that thing and
weaponize it to their own uses
but it's failed to acknowledge the kind
of like mytho poetic language
and utilize that it's just tried to
graft its own messages onto the courts
of the existing thing
which isn't going to work like you know
people are people are waking up to like
deep
uh ancient truths that perhaps a couple
of generations of people had had
had sort of hidden from them because
shit was so nice
and they hadn't had to think about those
things you know but
like you're concerned with hijacking
re-hijacking the culture right
stealing the culture feeling is how
you're playing it yeah
so it's going to be a case of um
a new methyl a new mythological language
or a new
new myths that incorporate all that
stuff
and tell the story of that in a way
that's like understandable to children
yeah that that resonates a lot and i'll
turn it over to
the group in a moment but how do you see
your role in that
yeah i'm just a humble dj a music making
guy you know i mean
he stumbled across some magic formulas
i was you know paying attention and shit
and uh you know my job
is uh the simple job of integrating the
wisdom
of the ages into sonic forms that we can
use to reprogram ourselves with
superpowers
and uh achieve uh achieve
uh alignment with our highest being
in this lifetime so that's my little
thing to do
you know over here in this space
amen brother all right uh daniel if
you're going to mute yourself and ask
secure your question
uh akira you so you've been in the music
industry for a long time
and i think i heard you say correct me
if i'm wrong but
that you've noticed that there's a seven
year cycle where
uh it's like punk kind of reacting to
the existing status quo and
punk kind of goes in this seven year
cycle and one of my favorite things you
said was that wholesomeness is the new
punk
and i'm just wondering if that's still
the case um and if not
where exactly are we now like what if
you have your finger on the pulse right
now how would you describe it
yeah well it oscillates between as far
as i can say it oscillates between
essentially psychedelic
and punk if you think of it in musical
movements that's one way of looking at
it
another way of looking at it is kind of
like uh colorful and
black and sort of dark or like you think
of it in terms of drugs it's like
ecstasy
to uh heroin should we say oh xanax was
the one in this
cycle right we went from seven years ago
it was odd future and it was tie-dye
t-shirts and it was everyone being all
nice with each other
then on the other side of it it's very
irish and dressing in black and
everyone's taking xanax and fucking
being miserable
right we currently as far as my
calculations go
this this this summer was
according to my my chart gonna be peak
dark
like so the peak of that punk neither
dark goth whatever you want to call
it cycle then it swings back to
uh psychedelic so at this point the
psychedelic stuff has been bubbling up
from the underground for the past like
year or so
as it should be and we'll we'll hit this
slight peak
of sort of nihilistic ah terror or that
type of thing and then it plunges back
in the other direction
and every time it does this it hits
harder it's like a it's like a wrecking
ball
and uh that aligns up with the ways of
distributing it because now
everyone's on the flipping internet so
this time the psychedelic thing hits
there's not just going to be weirdos in
libraries you know
it's not going to be like a few of us
guys without like photocopying fanzines
and like terence mckenna or cassettes or
whatever the heck
it's like yeah auntie as everybody
so yeah that's that's specifically where
we are i think
according to my observations
wholesomeness is yes definitely still
very punk because uh
if you look at what's mainstream and
what's been pushed on a very very
mainstream
level it is the opposite of that so
do the math uh getting married uh
taking extreme personal responsibility
having a family
being nice to people uh being civil
that's punk
as fuck that
carl young quote is coming to mind i'd
rather be whole than good
okay there you go uh he said
siddhar if you're going to meet yourself
hey man um i was just checking out your
work before this meeting
um and i had your i had a question about
rap like
how um you see yourself fit into like
the i guess i feel like a similar kind
of nihilism exists in like the hip-hop
world as well
like someone like lil b um he's like a
rapper from the bay area he's like
all about uh he's called base god little
b i don't know if you don't know about
him or like how many people know about
him but
for me it seemed like he seemed to have
a similar sentiment to yours
um or like at least in terms of the
artistic project into bringing
positivity to the space
yeah a little bit he's a friend of mine
um like
well we text each other and i've been
i've performed with him and stuff like
that
and he sends me a text message like once
a month that just says i love you he's
very sweet guy
uh and if you notice he was uh
really influential and powerful
culturally between 2009 and 2012
which was kind of the height of the last
kind of psychedelic swing
you know and then anyway zoom back in
the other direction and people didn't
want to hear that little b
bass god like everything's beautiful
shit he was he's possibly the most
influential artist of his generation
uh in a way uh between him and chief
keef but certainly yeah
things went super nihilistic again after
that but if you remember when he was
popping it was him and odd future
were kind of running around being all
colorful and joyful and
integrated with all their friends and
they weren't worried about fucking they
didn't think racism existed
they would both literally come out with
these statements like what racism and
easing fucking real like grow the fuck
up faggot
was one tyler the creator quote um
but that was then and then things went
in the other direction uh and they will
go back again you see it starting to
happen now in rap you see sort of like
result
from people like that starting to come
up and it's starting to get a bit more
hippie again and a bit more
loose uh the music is becoming less
starting to become a lot less quantized
starts to loosen up a bit
trap has been dominant right that lex
luger uh
sub bass angry hi-hat dark gothic sort
of
vibes that's been dominant for seven
years that's starting to
that'll basically watch over the next
year like that
will go again and rap's been doing this
from the from the whole all of rap's
existence that is swung between the kind
of happy
the happy joyful disco side of rap to
the dark gangster
angry nihilist whatever it is side of
rap
two and four it goes
tyson you have a question yeah and now
this
my question kind of relates to my
experience of
odd future and how exciting that was for
my friends and i
to see this clan look like love and life
together
and how that inspired us at the time um
and so i'm noticing like i've been very
inspired by
and the heroes myth um
yeah the hero's journey myth and that
story and now i'm noticing like this
move in toward like what are the new
myths and new stories
about the tribal journey or like what is
that and
um sort of very excited about
participating and
creating some of these stories well i'm
curious is there a story or a new myth
that's been most alive to you
particularly around this idea of
yeah the tribe well i think you had it
there when you said participation that's
the clue
because what happened was when the
printed press came along
prior to that we were participatory in
the myth
everyone told the story together sat
around in a campfire whatever the hell
it was
you say the bit that you remember people
carrying whole books in their brains you
know
printing press comes along and suddenly
it gets individualized and atomized
and then corporations come along and
disney comes along and it buys all the
myths
and you can't participate in the myths
you've got to write fan fiction on a
reddit board
and you get booted off of twitter and
you care about the myths
so when they come along and destroy the
myths you're upset and you care and you
go
you use whatever form you have which is
a youtube video or and you say you're
destroying my myth and they go shut up
it's the phobe
and they stomp on you and you're not
allowed to participate in the myth and
that's a
messed up thing for culture so what's
exciting about now is the
the beginning of this new way of
co-collaboration in the creation of the
new myth which is
which will be without disney and without
that it'll be you know it's going to be
in a different language in a different
form
it's going to be uh i think a song that
we all sing together and we'll write
together
and it's just beginning
amen um arie
i want to hear your voice man she said
you have a question for akira i know you
didn't
write anything in the chat box
dude peter so good to see you here and
yeah
kyra thanks for being here so stoked to
uh
to be here with you i've got my
eight-year-old great dane who's having
some just like traumatic
health issues today that i'm just like
kind of fucking frazzled with but
i am i would be curious to hear
like like obviously i think that
so much of the stuff that you're
sampling in your music
is the stuff that resonates with me but
like furthermore like what is
what is it about these
people these myths that you're so pulled
by to
especially the stuff that you're
sampling in the music
you mean the the the the words or the
music itself yeah the words it's
the words and and i guess that just your
delineation of that brings up for me
what is the connection between the beat
and the words
yeah i mean that's one of those
mysterious things there's a case of i
like i kind of listen to the words and i
say what is the sound of these words
what's the right sound of music for it
and
i kind of work that out usually very
quickly and it usually suggests itself
very quickly
and then and the more of it you do the
the more you're able to do that and it's
a wonderful thing to be able to go okay
this is what elon musk sounds like and
then
you do it and it does uh but as far as
the people
you know you i would say as far as the
meaning wave project goes jordan
peterson would be the first guy right
and i kind of thought about it a bit in
the way that the marvel cinematic
universe was constructed
they had to begin the idea of the
fantastical superheroes they had was
just unpalatable to to normies
they had to begin with a guy who built
himself a suit in a cave
he was a rich guy and he was smart
scientist so making a suit in a cave
didn't seem too crazy
so you have the idea of iron man and
that was jordan peterson
you know he's a guy he's he's talking
sense it's all seems very logical
there's little hints of kind of like
weirdo stuff but
nothing that seems too crazy it kind of
makes sense and then that leads into
people like joseph campbell and people
like that you have alan watts come along
he's maybe a doctor strange type figure
stuff of that nature and you can build
this story and you can tell
you can tell the story which is the
story of the history of humanity and the
future of humanity
through the wisdom of these bad
motherfuckers uh of the ages and you
could what i'm trying to do is build
upon each thing
so that you can go along and it makes
sense
you know sort of like you can go on the
journey and it makes sense and you
understand
you're not just thrown into guardians of
the galaxy and it just seems fucking
weird
you know uh how much of that was like a
plan were you like
did you just hear some jordan peterson
and reads and jordan peterson and get
inspired by his work and want to
integrate it into your music or was like
was there some kind of vision that you
had
before you started the meaning wave
project that was like you were going to
bring
meaningful words into music that people
listen to
yeah i mean i stopped rapping because i
wasn't
wise and smart enough to make the album
i wanted to make
i had this trilogy in mind i made the
first two records
the first was about being young and the
being the individual the right of the
individual to be individual it had
prisoner samples in it and all that the
second one was about when the individual
realizes it's part of a greater whole
interfaces with the greater world you
grow up a bit
then the third one i couldn't make it
because i was like shit i'm not smart
enough i'm not wise enough
i'm going to do this so then it was like
all right i'm gonna have to go focus on
like making music like instrumentally
and just like
learning i need to have a kid i need to
become a father or i need to like you
know get married i need to
go out into the world and learn this
stuff so i can put this stuff in music
because i realized that
the vast majority of pop music only uh
described the experience of the teenager
essentially like the emotional
experience of the teenager was like 95
of music and it seemed like such a
wasted opportunity with music being so
powerful
you know so i wanted to i wanted to go
out and be able to do this and initially
i thought i would do it by wrapping
i'd go out get smart and then put that
stuff in wraps and then along the way
i was experimenting with sampling spoken
word stuff
and uh that basically developed as a way
of
i was like holy shit like you know i can
have
yeah i can have jordan peterson rapping
on the record he's been thinking about
40 40 years i don't have to try and
fucking like newbie my way into a vague
understanding of fucking youngie and
whatever the fuck
i can get jordan pieces of just pieces
and just fucking break it down everyone
raps anyway you listen to anyone talking
they all talking in rhythm there's
melody and everything you just got to
fucking listen and find it
and our boy tyson here uh do you want to
come off you tyson just say what you're
doing uh
tomorrow yeah i'm uh highlighting that
reality that everyone raps
and that when we are speaking we're
communing with rhythm and poetry
and creating a space for us all
freestyle together and experience group
flow
through freestyle rap and music yeah
yeah you should go to that you should
come that tomorrow akira we have this
like freestyle through
the pandemic and we're just using like
freestyle rap as a spiritual exercise to
be
uh to be loyal to your word
amen he did the base freestyle he would
just let it
out and he would put it all he would
just release it as mixtapes and outputs
you just literally just sit there and
just restart for like two hours and then
put it out as an album at the end of the
two hours
[Music]
so we have three minutes to the hour uh
do you have time for another question
should we bounce to the other link
let's say one more question then we'll
bounce over the other link cool and then
we can carry
in there rhea
you got a question yeah
um first of all i just want to say i'm
so appreciative of your contribution to
the world because
um some of my most blissful moments in
life
is like that 2 a.m spot of the night
and that music is just like so good and
everyone's vibing and
it really is just like oh
the times that i feel most at one with
the universe and the times i feel like i
most understand what life is all about
so when you were describing that earlier
just like really
i could viscerally feel that and i'm so
appreciative of that
um and my question is do you believe
myth
shapes culture or does culture shape
myth and
what is music's role in like or its
contribution
um to the myth that we're creating
uh myth does myth shape culture or does
she culture shape
myth yeah myth is a language that
describes the indescribable right and
myth is the language that that puts
like the sum uh totality of everything
we've learned over the course of
development as humans
into something that can be understood uh
by everybody so
the myth i would say comes first
but uh the sh what the myth looks like
because the myth is always the same
essentially but then it's packaged in a
different way you know
it's like a different avatar so then the
avatar will take some reflection of
the culture uh
so but what's the thing i was thinking
recently
they would say politics is downstream
from culture
culture is downstream from vibes so
vibes overall is
is so that's the thing you want to
really focus on and that's the thing
everybody can do
everybody can focus on vibes i.e their
vibration i
how their you know uh how they're
vibrating out in the world
and like that is what's gonna like shape
uh the mythology you get
because if you're not vibing with what
they're trying to give you as a version
of the mythology while you're still sort
of like
uh allowing other people to create the
mythology for you
if like your vibes reject the ones they
try and create they won't become the
mythology what becomes the mythology is
that which you resonate with
right so while we've been in this uh
non-participatory culture of kind of
accepting a sort of product of mythology
that's
given to us we got given star wars we
got given the lion king
whatever it was right uh that was only
allowed to happen because we resonated
with it and we vibed with it we're like
yeah that's dope
we've stopped doing that lately there
isn't a new official mythology yet we're
about to build one like i was saying i
think we're going to be doing that in a
more participate participatory fashion
and these little zoom meetings and
things like that that are popping up
during this
so-called crisis uh are a clue
as to how that's going to be forming uh
yeah i don't know if that answers that
fully but that's what i'm thinking on
that thing at a moment
all right so that was uh delicious um uh
we got to get you back akira i would
love to have you back
for a proper one step six feet in that
direction and press
a button and uh then it will be like a
whole new
whole new digital experience which is
pretty cool
so they just have to go to this link
right here right the youtube link right
now
yeah all right so i'll stop recording
this one
like right now that should be working
right now
um catalog no not catalog
i'm sending over a track that i was